♪Wind♪
♪ الرياح ♪
♪Incidentally blows away fascinating whispers of love♪
♪ يضرب عرضا بيادق الحب الرائعة ♪
♪Whispers of love♪
♪ حراس الحب ♪
♪Sound the best with loyalty to the only valentine♪
♪ دق أفضل بالولاء إلى الوصية الوحيدة ♪
♪The prosperous life♪
♪ الحياة المزدهرة ♪
♪Is when we are together all year round♪
♪ هو عندما نكون معا على مدار السنة ♪
♪For the rest of my life♪
♪ لبقية حياتي ♪
♪All I want is a perfect love with you♪
♪ كل ما أريد هو حبك المثالي ♪
♪I'll remain elegant for you all my life♪
♪ سأبقى أنيقة لك طوال حياتي ♪
♪Giving you my love little by little♪
♪ إعطائك حبي شيئًا فشيئًا ♪
♪I care for you with every piece of my heart♪
♪ أنا أهتم بك في كل قلبي ♪
♪And I miss you every day and night♪
♪ وأنا أشتاق إليك كل ليلة ♪
♪I'll be loyal to you in the best years of my life♪
♪ سأكون مخلصا لك في أفضل سنوات حياتي ♪
♪Melting love with gentle smiles♪
♪ تميّز الحب بالأعمدة الحمقاء ♪
♪I won't be afraid of anything♪
♪ لن أشعر بالخوف من أي شيء ♪
♪And I won't change my heart for you♪
♪ لن أغيّر قلبي من أجلك ♪
=Jade's Fateful Love=
= حب اليشم المؤلم =
=Episode 6=
= الحلقة 6 =
Su Nian,
سو نيان
so,
لذلك
you let go of that man last time
تركته من ذلك الرجل المرة الماضية
and now you can make use of him.
والآن يمكنك الاستفادة منه
Actually, I'm not sure if he'll come.
في الواقع، لست متأكدًا من أنه سيأتي
As a lady, gorgeous, smart,
سيدة رائعة ذكية
mysterious, and stylish,
غامضة وأنيقة
you're irresistible to all men in this world.
أنت لا يقاوم جميع الرجال في هذا العالم
It's so sweet of you.
إنه حلو جدًا منك
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي يا صاحب السمو
A lady outside our mansion
سيدة خارج قصتنا
asked me to give Mr. Xingyi this invitation.
طلبت مني أن أعطي السيد شينغ يي هذه الدعوة
(Invitation)
(دعوة)
Lady?
سيدة؟
Who is that lady?
من تلك السيدة؟
"Gentleman, I adored you as I met you.
"أيها الفتى، لقد أحضرتك وأنا قابلتك
After you left, I asked around
بعد أن غادرت، سألتك في كل مكان
and finally got to know you worked for the princess.
وأخيرًا تعرفت على أنك عملت من أجل الأميرة
I hereby invite you
أدعوك بموجب هذا
to a chat in the House of Romance."
إلى محادثة في مجلس الرومانسية "
Adore?
تعساء؟
She adores me?
إنها تقحمني؟
Why do I feel scared?
لماذا أشعر بالخوف؟
Maybe that is only
ربما هذا هو فقط
her pleasantry.
مالها العام
She just wants to talk, I guess.
إنها تريد التحدث فحسب، أعتقد ذلك
Oh,
أوه
have you found the evidence for her being an assassin?
هل وجدت الدليل على أنها قاتل؟
No, actually.
لا، في الواقع
So,
لذلك
stop slandering Miss Su.
توقف عن الافتراء على الآنسة سو
This is weird.
هذا غريب
I'd like to see what she's up to.
أود أن أرى ما الذي تفعله
You're going again?
هل ستذهب مجددًا؟
Don't make trouble!
لا تثيري المشاكل!
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك
Wait for me.
انتظرني
Hey, Your Grace.
مهلًا يا غرامك
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
Her Highness went out again.
خرجت صاحبة السمو مرة أخرى
Are our dark guards following her?
هل يتبعها حراس الظلام؟
Nie Chen is following her with his men.
ني تشن يتابعها مع رجاله
Shiyu.
شييو
- Shiyu. - Your Grace.
- شيو - غريسك
Since you came back from Dongyu,
منذ عودتك من دونغيو
you've seldom visited me.
لم تزرني إلا نادرا
Lately, I have too many official and private things to do.
في الآونة الأخيرة، لديّ الكثير من الأشياء الرسمية والخاصة لأفعلها
Yeah, Your Grace.
نعم يا غربك
His Highness has to go to the palace soon.
يجب على سموه الذهاب إلى القصر قريبا
You're going there as soon as I come.
ستذهب إلى هناك بمجرد أن آتي
Shiyu, are you alienating me
شيو هل تطردني
just because you're engaged?
فقط لأنك مخطوب؟
Princess of Dongyu is my consort.
أميرة دونغيو هي قرينتي
I should care about her.
يجب أن أعتني بها
Shiyu, now you really
شييو، الآن أنت حقا
care for that Dongyu woman, huh?
هل تهتم بتلك المرأة من دونغيو، هوه؟
Luoyi, she is your cousin-in-law.
لويي، إنها زوجة عمك
Show some respect.
أظهري بعض الاحترام
I won't!
لن أفعل!
(Zhenlai Store) Xingyi, how about this?
(متجر زينلاي) شينغ يي، ماذا عن هذا؟
Let's stop giving Miss Su Nian a hard time,
دعنا نتوقف عن صعوبة إعطاء الآنسة سو تيان
shall we?
هل نفعل ذلك؟
Yueling, you get it wrong.
يويلينغ، أنت مخطئة
She gives me a hard time.
إنها تسبب لي المتاعب
But she...
لكنها...
Let go of me!
اتركني!
Attention, everybody.
انتباه، الجميع
(Huangsi Restaurant) She's the slave
(مطعم هوانغسي) إنها الرقيق
I bought with money.
اشتريت بالمال
How can I just release her?
كيف يمكنني أن أفرج عنها؟
She can't be released.
لا يمكن إطلاق سراحها
I've collected enough money to redeem myself.
لقد جمعت ما يكفي من المال لإنقاذ نفسي
Why can I not be released?
لماذا لا يمكن إطلاق سراحي؟
Because you're from Dongyu.
لأنك من دونغيو
Oh, she's from Dongyu.
إنها من دونغيو
Dongyu people can't be redeemed.
لا يمكن استرجاع شعب دونغيو
Why?
لماذا؟
In the Capital City,
في العاصمة
Dongyu people are just pariahs.
أهل دونغيو منبوذون فقط
Redeem? Funny.
لتعلم؟ مضحك
Mr. Huang has a point.
السيد هوانغ منطقي
Dongyu people are ungrateful.
شعب دونغيو غير ممتن
Ungrateful.
غير ممتن
Yeah. They're ungrateful people.
نعم هم أشخاص جادون
- Ungrateful people.
- أشخاص غير ممتنين - الناس العازبون
Why do Dongyu people
لماذا شعب دونغيو
have to be slaves here?
يجب أن يكونوا عبيدًا هنا؟
Where are you from, stranger?
من أين أنت يا غريب؟
How do you not know this rule?
كيف لا تعرفين هذه القاعدة؟
If she wasn't a slave,
إن لم تكن رقيقًا
she would be unregistered and homeless.
وهي غير مسجلة ولا مأوى
Detected by the government, anyone like this
كشفت الحكومة هذا الأمر
has to be expelled from the Capital City!
يجب أن يتم طرده من العاصمة
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Yeah. Don't let her go.
نعم لا تدعها تذهب
Release this girl.
أطلق سراح هذه الفتاة
Or I'll be rude to you.
أو سأكون فظا معك
Interfere with my business?
تتدخل في عملي؟
You must have a death wish.
لا بد أن لديك أمنية في الموت
They beat me!
ضربوني!
Help!
النجدة!
Hel...
هيا
Officer, help me.
ساعدني أيها الضابط
These two guys stand up for this Dongyu slave
هذان الرجلان يقفان من أجل ربح دونغيو هذا
and they even want to kill me.
ويريدون قتلي حتى
Do me justice, please.
احققوا لي العدالة من فضلك
You bullied her first.
لقد تنمر عليها أولًا
How dare you talk nonsense and slander us?
كيف تجرئين على التفوه بالهراء والتشهير بنا؟
Don't trust their nonsense.
لا تثق بهراء
Arrest them. Arrest them.
قم بتوقيعهم
Take them away!
خذوهم بعيدا
Yeah. Take them away.
نعم خذوهم بعيدا
Arrest them.
اقبض عليهم
Go.
اذهب
Let me go.
اتركني
Let me go!
اتركني!
(The Capital Government)
(حكومة العاصمة)
Let us out, you people!
دعنا نخرج أيها الناس!
I'm innocent.
أنا بريء
I'm innocent. I really am.
أنا بريء، أنا كذلك حقًا
Let us out of here.
دعينا نخرج من هنا
Don't you know who we are?
ألا تعرفين من نكون؟
I'm innocent.
أنا بريء
Somebody! Somebody come!
شخص ما! شخص ما يأتي!
Where are you from, stranger?
أين أنت من الغريب؟
How do you not know this rule?
كيف لا تعرفين هذه القاعدة؟
If she wasn't a slave,
إن لم تكن رقيقًا
she would be unregistered and homeless.
وهي غير مسجلة ولا مأوى
Detected by the government, anyone like this
كشفت الحكومة هذا الأمر
has to be expelled from the Capital City!
يتعين طرده من العاصمة!
I'm Qiyun,
أنا كيون
thank you for helping me.
شكرا لك على مساعدتي
Not at all, Miss.
لا على الإطلاق، الآنسة
We didn't actually help.
لم نساعدك في الحقيقة
I got you into this.
أدخلتك إلى هذا
You stood up for Dongyu people in public.
لقد وقفت إلى جانب شعب دونغيو في مكان عام
In the Capital City,
في العاصمة
this is really rare.
هذا نادر حقا
I never knew
لم أكن أعرف أبدا
life was so hard for Dongyu people
كانت الحياة صعبة جدا لشعب دونغيو
in the Capital City.
في العاصمة
What's worse,
ما هو أسوأ
they say
يقولون
Dongyu people are pariahs.
أهل دونغيو منبوذون
In Beishuo,
في بيشوه
there are pariahs and civilians.
وهناك
Three generations of criminals
ثلاثة أجيال من المجرمين
are the sinners.
هم الأشرار
Music workers in entertainment places
عمال الموسيقى في الأماكن الترفيهية
are musicians.
هم موسيقيون
In the Capital City,
في العاصمة
those who stay for work
أولئك الذين يقيمون من أجل العمل
without private estates
بدون عقارات خاصة
are slaves.
هم عبيد
Sinners, musicians, and slaves
المصممون والموسيقيون والعبيد
are all pariahs?
جميعهم منبوذون؟
(In Beishuo,)
(في بيشو،)
(people have to obey this terrible hierarchy.)
(يجب على الناس طاعة هذا التسلسل الهرمي الرهيب)
(The North Prince's Mansion)
(حفل الأمير الشمالي)
Your Grace.
غريسك
We just got the information
حصلنا للتو على المعلومات
that the Princess of Dongyu and her guard
أن أميرة دونغ يو وحارسها
were imprisoned in the Capital Government by mistake.
تم سجنهم في حكومة العاصمة بالخطأ
It's really something new.
إنه حقا شيء جديد
Shiyu didn't send anyone to save her?
ألم يرسل شيو أحد لإنقاذها؟
His Highness is in the palace now.
سموه في القصر الآن
Just her luck.
مجرد حظها
Your brother always wants you
أخوك يريدك دائما
to marry the North Prince.
الزواج من الأمير الشمالي
But the Princess of Dongyu
ولكن أميرة دونغيو
makes His Highness care less about you.
تجعل سموه يهتم بك أقل
In my opinion, when His Highness is away now,
في رأيي، عندما يكون سموه بعيدا الآن
why don't we give her a lesson?
لماذا لا نعطيها درسا؟
How?
كيف؟
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
We can first do this
يمكننا أولًا فعل هذا
and then...
وبعد ذلك
Shiyu, do you think
شيو، هل تعتقد
we can win this game?
يمكننا الفوز في هذه اللعبة؟
It's hard to win.
من الصعب الفوز
But we may not lose, either.
لكن قد لا نخسر أيضًا
We must do easy things before hard ones.
يجب أن نفعل أشياء سهلة من قبل أشياء صعبة
Small things before great ones.
الأشياء الصغيرة قبل الأشياء الكبيرة
Shiyu, I admire your determination
شي يو، أنا معجب بتصميمك
of this game.
من هذه اللعبة
Playing all alone,
وإذ ألعب كل شيء بمفردي
I had to push my enemy into the trap.
اضطررت إلى دفع عدوي إلى الفخ
But I got you into trouble many times.
لكنني وضعتها في ورطة مرات عديدة
I feel quite guilty.
أنا مذنب تماما
Brother, you and I
أيها الأخ، أنا وأنت
have been stuck in the same crisis.
كنا عالقين في نفس الأزمة
To get rid of this crisis,
للتخلص من هذه الأزمة
I'm willing to be your weapon.
أنا على استعداد لأن أكون سلاحك
When you and I work of one mind,
عندما نعمل أنا وأنت من عقل واحد
even if we're weak and all alone,
حتى لو كنا ضعفين ووحدنا
we'll still be able to turn the tide and win.
و
(Hall of Politics)
(قاعة السياسة)
Eunuch Li, something terrible happened.
الخصي لي، حدث شيء فظيع
Please tell His Highness about it.
من فضلك أخبر الأمير عن ذلك
But...
ولكن...
His Majesty is playing chess with the North Prince in there.
جلالة الإمبراطور يلعب الشطرنج مع أمير الشمال هناك
No one is allowed to disturb them.
لا يُسمح لأحد بإزعاجهم
Eunuch Li, this is really urgent.
الخصي لي، هذا أمر عاجل حقا
Please, Eunuch Li.
من فضلك، الخصي لي
Sir, you look really anxious.
سيدي، تبدو قلقا حقا
I'll get in and tell them, then.
سأدخل وخبرهم، إذن
Thank you, Eunuch Li.
شكرا لك، الخصي لي
Somebody!
في أي مكان!
Anybody there?
أي شخص هناك؟
Let us out!
دعنا نخرج!
Let us out of here.
دعنا نخرج من هنا
Yueling, don't be scared.
يول، لا تكن خائفا
When the mayor interrogates us,
عندما يستجوبنا العمدة
we'll tell them who we are.
سنخبرهم من نحن
Then he won't dare to be so rude.
إذن لن يجرؤ على أن يكون بهذه الوقاحة
I'm not scared.
أنا لست خائفة
I just didn't know
أنا فقط لم أكن أعرف
Dongyu people had to be slaves
كان يتعين أن يكون شعب دونغيو عبيدا
in the Capital City.
في العاصمة
Come in, please, My Lord.
تعال، من فضلك، يا ملك
Is that Wen Yu?
هل هذا ون يو؟
Do you mean them?
هل تقصدهم؟
Yes. The two of them.
نعم، كلاهما
They made a scene on the street.
قاما بمشهد في الشارع
How silly!
يا للسخافة!
They're the North Prince's guests.
إنهم ضيوف الأمير الشمالي
How dare you mistreat them?
كيف تجرؤ على إساءة معاملتهم؟
Sorry, I didn't recognize them.
آسف، لم أستطع التعرف عليهم
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Go open the door.
افتح الباب
Yes.
نعم
Come in, please, My Lord.
تعال، من فضلك يا سيدي
Sorry, we did you an injustice.
آسف، فعلنا لك ظلما
His Highness sent someone to tell us
أرسل سموه شخصا ليخبرنا
you were his guests.
أنت كنت ضيفاته
I checked it carefully,
راجعت ذلك بعناية
only to find it's just a misunderstanding
فقط لأجده مجرد سوء تفاهم
So, can we leave now?
لذلك، هل يمكننا المغادرة الآن؟
Yes, of course.
بالطبع نعم
We'll take her out, too.
سنخرجها أيضًا
No.
لا
Her master has come to get her back.
لقد جاء معلمها ليعيدها
He's waiting out there.
إنه ينتظر هناك
He won't be good to her.
لن يليق بها
Why can't she leave with us?
لماذا لا تستطيع المغادرة معنا؟
She's still a slave
لا تزال عبودية
and can't leave without permission.
ولا يمكنها المغادرة دون إذن
This is against the national law.
هذا يخالف القانون الوطني
(The Capital Government)
(حكومة العاصمة)
Come over.
هيا
Take her away.
خذها بعيدا
If it happens again,
إذا حدث الأمر مرة أخرى
see how I'll punish you!
انظر كيف سأعاقب عليك!
Yueling, look.
يوان، انظر
The carriage from the North Prince.
العربة من الأمير الشمالي
This way, please, Your Highness.
بهذا الطريق، من فضلك، يا صاحب السمو
Did you come here alone?
هل جئت إلى هنا بمفردك؟
His Highness wanted us to keep a low profile
أراد سموه منا أن نحافظ على مستوى منخفض
instead of bringing the blame.
بدلا من إلقاء اللوم
So, I was sent here alone.
لذلك، تم إرسالي إلى هنا وحدي
Fine.
حسنا
Are we there yet?
ألم نصل بعد؟
This isn't the way back.
هذه ليست طريقة العودة
Where are you taking us?
إلى أين ستأخذنا؟
Give it to me.
أعطيه إلي
Xingyi.
شينغ يي
You...
أنت...
Yueling.
يوي لينغ
Yueling!
تشينغ!
Xingyi, Xingyi.
شينغ يي
Xingyi, wake up.
شينغ يي، استيقظ
We are trapped.
نحن محاصرون
One, two, three.
واحد اثنان ثلاثة
Your Highness, Her Highness was kidnapped to Shili Hill.
صاحبة السمو، تم اختطافها إلى تل شيلي
Gather our men to fight there.
اجمع رجالنا القتال هناك
Yes.
نعم
Hyah.
هاي
Change of plan.
تغيير الخطة
The North Princess Consort isn't coming here tonight.
قرينة الأميرة الشمالية لن تأتي إلى هنا الليلة
You leave now.
تغادرين الآن
I'm afraid
أنا خائف أنه
you can't leave.
لا يمكنك المغادرة
Your Highness,
صاحبة السمو
the groom confessed everything.
اعترف العريس بكل شيء
They were sent by Princess Luoyi.
كانت أرسلتها الأميرة لويي
Luoyi?
لويي؟
Yes.
نعم
How shall we deal with these dark guards
كيف يجب أن نتعامل مع هؤلاء الحراس الظالمين
from her family?
من عائلتها؟
Kill them all.
اقتلوهم جميعا
Yes.
نعم
Wen Yu.
وين يو
Wen Yu!
وين يو!
- Your Highness.
- صاحب السمو
Is Her Grace back?
هل عادت غريزها؟
- No.
- لا
Yueling.
يويلينغ
Wen Yu.
وين يو
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
Glad you're fine.
أنت بخير
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبّل حاجباك ♪
I just haven't seen you for one day.
لم أرك منذ يوم واحد فقط
Why were you even imprisoned?
لماذا كنت في السجن حتى؟
Come on.
هيا
There are not only a lot of rules in Beishuo,
هناك ليس فقط الكثير من القواعد في بيشوه
but also a terrible hierarchy.
بل أيضا التسلسل الهرمي الرهيب
What hierarchy?
أي التسلسل الهرمي؟
Miss Qiyun, I mean.
الآنسة تشيون، أعني
The Dongyu girl we tried to save today.
فتاة دونغيو التي حاولنا إنقاذها اليوم
I never knew Dongyu people
لم أكن أعرف أبدا شعب دونغيو
had to live
كان عليهم العيش
such a miserable life in Beishuo.
مثل هذه الحياة البائسة في بيشوه
She's still a slave
لا تزال رجلًا
and can't ever be released.
ولا يمكن إطلاق سراحها أبدًا
How could there be such a ridiculous law?
كيف يمكن أن يكون هناك قانون سخيف كهذا؟
What do you want to do, then?
ماذا تريدين أن تفعلي إذًا؟
I'm the Princess of Dongyu.
أنا أميرة دونغيو
Since I'm here,
بما أنني هنا
I must get my people out of their misery
يجب أن أخرج شعبي من البؤس
and abolish this law for them.
وإلغاء هذا القانون لهم
Yueling, you're ambitious
يينغ، أنت طموح
and you care for your people.
وأنت تهتم بشعبك
But you can't abolish this law
لكنك لا يمكنك إلغاء هذا القانون
in a very short time.
في وقت قصير جدا
And you can't change anything all alone.
ولا يمكنك تغيير أي شيء بمفردك
I totally understand.
فهمت تمامًا
But I can't just watch and do nothing.
لكنني لا أستطيع المشاهدة ولا أفعل شيئا
Wen Yu,
ون يو
can you do something to help me?
هل يمكنك القيام بشيء لمساعدتي؟
All I can do
كل ما يمكنني فعله
is try my best.
هو بذل قصارى جهدي
But it was really dangerous today.
لكنه كان خطيرًا جدًا اليوم
In the future, don't go out alone
في المستقبل، لا تخرجي وحدي
unless I'm around.
ما لم أكون هنا
(Benign and Benevolent)
(خير وخير)
Your Grace, have something to eat.
غريسك، لديك شيء لتأكله
How could you not eat anything?
كيف لك ألا تأكل أي شيء؟
Yueling, I'm back.
يويلينغ، لقد عدت
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Oh, so many delicious dishes.
أوه، الكثير من الأطباق اللذيذة
Did you make inquiries about Qiyun?
هل أجرت تحقيقات بشأن تشيون؟
As instructed by you,
وفقا لتعليمات منك
I sent some money and clothes to Qiyun.
أرسلت بعض المال والملابس إلى تشيون
Then Mr. Huang became less rude
ثم أصبح السيد هوانغ أقل فظاظة
to her.
لديها
That's good.
هذا جيد
Good.
جيد
This part looks so annoying.
هذا الجزء يبدو مزعجا جدا
Your Grace, Your Grace.
عرشك
The North Prince is here.
الأمير الشمالي هنا
The North Prince?
الأمير الشمالي؟
Shiyu.
شيو
Since my cousin, the Lord of the South, defended the border,
منذ ابن عمي، ملك الجنوب، دافع عن الحدود
he's trusted me with you.
إنه يثق بي معك
I think I've been taking good care of you.
أعتقد أنني كنت أعتني بك جيدا
I really wonder
أتساءل حقًا
what I've done wrong to you.
ما الخطأ الذي ارتكبته بالنسبة لك
Nothing. Why do you say that, Shiyu?
لا شيء لماذا تقول هذا يا شيو؟
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
why did you hurt Her Highness?
لماذا آذيت صاحبة السمو؟
I don't know what you're talking about, Shiyu.
لا أعرف ما الذي تتحدث عنه يا شي يو
I don't understand. I...
لا أفهم أنا
The special secret weapon of your dark guards.
السلاح السري الخاص لحرّاس الظلام
Others may not recognize it. But I can.
قد لا يتعرف الآخرون على ذلك، لكن يمكنني ذلك
I...
أنا...
I just meant to scare her.
كنت أريد إخافتها فحسب
I wouldn't really kill her.
ما كنت لأقتلها حقًا
Ping'er can be my witness.
بينغ هي شاهدي
I just asked my guards
لقد طلبت فقط من حراسي
to scare your consort.
لتخويف قرينتك
That's true, Your Highness.
هذا صحيح يا صاحب السمو
Please don't be angry.
من فضلك لا تغضب
Her Grace wouldn't kill her.
ما كانت السماء لتقتلها
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
It's capable of you, Princess Luoyi.
إنها قادرة عليك يا أميرة لوي
Your guards dared to kill even without your order.
تجرأ حارسك على القتل حتى من دون طلبك
Looks like I don't need to worry.
يبدو أنني لا داعي للقلق
Staying in my small mansion
البقاء في قصتي الصغيرة
may do you an injustice.
ربما يمكنك من ظلم
Shiyu, are you kicking me out?
شيو، هل تركل مني؟
For that Dongyu woman, you...
تلك امرأة من دونغيو، أنت...
Shiyu, why do you defend her like this?
شيو، لماذا تدافع عنها هكذا؟
Let me say it again.
دعني أقول ذلك مرة أخرى
She is the North Princess Consort.
إنها قرينة الأميرة الشمالية
Shiyu, I'm wrong.
شيو، أنا مخطئة
I just lost my mind.
لقد فقدت عقلي للتو
Give me a second chance.
أعطيني فرصة ثانية
I'll behave myself
سأتصرف
and I won't be her enemy anymore.
ولن أكون عدوها بعد الآن
But Shiyu, don't kick me out.
لكن شيو لا تطردني
I beg you.
أتوسل إليك
Let me stay by your side.
دعني أبقى بجانبك
Somebody.
شخص ما
Send Princess Luoyi back to the palace
أرسل الأميرة لويي إلى القصر
and have her belongings cleared away, too.
وأُخرجت ممتلكاتها أيضا
Su Nian,
سو نيان
that Dongyu man
أن رجل دونغيو
and the woman in the portrait were taken away.
والمرأة في الصورة تم أخذها
And I saw them
وقد رأيتهم
followed by the dark guards of the North Prince.
يليها حراس مظلون من الأمير الشمالي
Dark guards of the North Prince?
حراس ظالمون من الأمير الشمالي؟
(Who are they?)
(من هم؟)
(What's their relationship with the North Prince?)
(ما هي علاقتهما بالأمير الشمالي؟)
Su Nian,
سو نيان
how about I kidnap that woman tonight
ماذا عن اختطاف تلك المرأة الليلة
and interrogate her?
واستجوابها؟
Don't.
لا تفعلي
You may alert the North Prince's men.
يمكنك إنذار رجال الأمير الشمالي
Then we'll be in trouble.
إذن سنكون في ورطة
I crossed paths with that Dongyu man.
عبرت الطريق مع ذلك الرجل من دونغيو
You go and have him come over.
أنت اذهب وأجبره على المجيء
But Su Nian...
لكن سو نيان...
Just do this.
فقط قم بعمل هذا
I have my plan.
لدي خطتي
Yes, Su Nian.
نعم، سو نيان
So, this is your plan to kill two birds with one stone?
إذن، هذه هي خطتك لقتل عصفورين بحجر واحد؟
If it had succeeded,
إذا كانت قد نجحت
the Princess of Dongyu would have been killed by Princess Luoyi.
أميرة دونغيو كانت ستقتلها الأميرة لويي
The alliance between the Lord of the South
التحالف بين ملك الجنوب
and the North Prince would collapse.
وأمير الشمال
Prime Minister, my plan was perfect.
رئيس الوزراء، كانت خطتي مثالية
But this is really weird.
لكن هذا غريب حقا
The Princess of Dongyu and the North Prince
أميرة دونغيو والأمير الشمالي
seem to foresee the future.
يبدو أنها تتوقع المستقبل
Foresee the future?
تتوقع المستقبل؟
I'm...
أنا...
I'm trying to figure out why they can do that.
أحاول معرفة لماذا يمكنهم فعل ذلك
Since the marriage thing,
منذ الزواج
you've been making mistakes.
لقد كنت ترتكب أخطاء
Lin Su,
لين سو
I gave you way too many chances.
لقد أعطيتك الكثير من الفرص
Prime Minister, please give me one last chance.
رئيس الوزراء، يرجى إعطني فرصة أخيرة
This time,
هذه المرة
I'll make sure the Princess of Dongyu dies.
سأحرص على وفاة أميرة دونغيو
Please give me one last chance.
أرجو أن تعطيني فرصة أخيرة
What is Zhou Shiyu doing lately?
ما الذي يفعله تشو مؤخرا؟
He sent someone to Liuzhou secretly.
أرسل شخصا إلى ليوتشو سرا
Nan Xun is stalking him.
نان شيون يطارده
Liuzhou?
ليوتشو؟
Miss Qiyun cooks so perfectly.
الآنسة تشيون تطهو بشكل مثالي
It's the taste of our hometown.
إنه مذاق مسكنا الأصلي
According to Miss Qiyun,
وفقا للآنسة تشي يون
the pastry will be our present.
المعجنات ستكون حاضرنا
Since we warned Mr. Huang last time,
بما أننا حذرنا السيد هوانغ المرة الماضية
she's been living a much better life.
إنها تعيش حياة أفضل بكثير
Glad to hear that.
يسرني أن أسمع ذلك
Let me taste some.
دعني تذوق بعضًا منه
The fresh milk cake tastes really good.
كعكة الحليب الطازج مذاقها جيد حقا
I'll leave this to Wen Yu.
سأترك هذا إلى وين يو
Wen Yu?
وين يو؟
Yueling,
يول
you can't be in love with him, can you?
لا يمكنك أن تكون في حبه، أليس كذلك؟
Lo... Love?
الحب؟
How's that possible?
كيف حال ذلك؟
I'll just thank him for saving my life.
سأشكره فقط على إنقاذ حياتي
Saving your life?
حفظ حياتك؟
Well,
إذن
I think I saw Wen Yu die for you.
أعتقد أنني رأيت وين يو يموت من أجلك
Die for me?
مت من أجلي؟
I had a dream before.
كان لديّ حلم من قبل
In the dream, you were killed
في الحلم، لقد قتلت
and Wen Yu killed himself for you.
وقتل وين يو نفسه من أجلك
That dream was so real.
كان ذلك الحلم حقيقيا جدا
Your Highness, don't be ridiculous.
صاحب السمو، لا تكن سخيفا
Her Grace is the North Princess Consort.
غريس هي قرينة الأميرة الشمالية
If she has some gossip with Wen Yu,
إذا كانت لديها بعض الأحجار مع ون يو
her reputation
سمعتها
will be ruined.
سيتم تدميرها
You must not talk nonsense.
يجب ألا تتحدثي هراء
But I always think
لكنني أعتقد دائما
Wen Yu and Yueling make a perfect couple.
وين يو ويويلينغ يجعلان ثنائي مثالية
(Wen Yu and I?)
(ون يو وأنا؟)
(Pleasant and Harmonious)
(ماهرة ومنسجمة)
(Stay Modest) Your Highness, at your command,
(الصامد) صاحب السمو، تحت قيادتك
Nie Chen has secretly gone to Liuzhou to take over
تشي تشن قد ذهب سرا إلى ليوتشو لتولي
(Memorial to the Throne) the private soldiers trained by Mr. Liu.
(ذكرى العرش) الجنود الخاصون الذين قام السيد ليو بتدريبهم
I get it. Leave me.
فهمت، دعني أفعل هذا
Anything else?
أي شيء آخر؟
Your Highness, there's a small thing
صاحب السمو، هناك شيء صغير
I think I should tell you.
أعتقد أنني يجب أن أقول لك
Go ahead.
هيا
Lately, Her Highness has been
في الآونة الأخيرة، كانت صاحبة السمو
looking for a martial guard named Wen Yu.
تبحث عن حارس قتالي يُدعى ون يو
(I think it's time to tell her)
(أعتقد أن الوقت قد حان لإخبارها)
(who I really am.)
(من أنا حقًا)
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Smells so good.
رائحتها جيدة جدًا
Here.
تفضل
Thanks.
شكرًا
How much is the sugar?
كم ثمن السكر؟
Two wen for half a kilo. [*ancient Chinese penny]
وين لنصف كيلو [* فلس صيني قديم]
You're looking for me, huh?
أنت تبحث عني، هوه؟
Why are you stalking me
لماذا ترصدني
so sneakily?
صرافة جدا؟
I'm the maid of Miss Su Nian,
أنا خادمة الآنسة سو نيان
the unsurpassed lady in the House of Romance.
السيدة غير متجاوزة في مجلس الرومانسية
She wants to invite you to a chat.
إنها تريد دعوتك إلى محادثة
So, she sent me to get you there.
لذلك، أرسلتني للوصل بك إلى هناك
Su Nian?
سو نيان؟
Yes, exactly.
نعم، بالضبط
I'm not going.
لن أذهب
You and your lady are weird.
أنت وسيدتك غريبان
What kind of invitation is this?
أي نوع من هذه الدعوات؟
Just now, I saw you doing some shopping
الآن، رأيتك تفعلين بعض التسوق
very happily.
لحسن الحظ
So, I didn't dare to disturb you.
لذلك، لم أجرؤ على إزعاجي
Please don't blame me.
أرجوك لا تلومني
Forget it. You go back and tell her
انس الأمر، عد وأخبرها
that I mistook her for someone else.
أنني ظننت أنها شخص آخر
Sorry to have offended her.
آسف على السخرية منها
But she must not have any intentions
ولكن لا يجب أن يكون لديها أي نوايا
towards me just because of this.
تجاهي فقط لهذا السبب
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
how about you go and tell her personally?
ماذا عن أن تذهب وتخبرها شخصيا؟
Miss Su Nian has been waiting for you the whole day.
سو نيان كانت في انتظارك طوال اليوم
She is the unsurpassed lady.
إنها السيدة لم يسبق لها مثيل
But in private,
ولكن على انفراد
she has never met a young man before.
لم يسبق لها أن قابلت شابا
If you don't go,
إذا لم تذهب
I will not know how to explain this.
لن أعرف كيف أشرح هذا
When I'm back,
عندما أعود
I will certainly be punished.
سوف أُعاقب بالتأكيد
It's my fault.
إنه خطأي
I shouldn't have stalked you
ما كان ينبغي لي أن أطمئن
and you even misunderstood me.
ولا بد أنك أسأت فهمي
Fine, then.
حسنًا إذن
You take me there.
خذني إلى هناك
All right.
حسنًا
Miss Qianqian,
الآنسة تشيان
the jerky sticks look quite delicious.
تبدو العصي الجميلة لذيذة جدا
Mr. Lin?
السيد لين؟
Your Highness
صاحبة السمو
doesn't allow our princess to enter the western yard, huh?
لا يسمح أميرتنا بالدخول إلى الفناء الغربي، هو؟
What are you doing here, then?
ماذا تفعل هنا إذن؟
Miss Qianqian,
الآنسة تشيان
did you eat too many jerky sticks?
هل أكلت الكثير من العصي الغاضبة؟
Why are you so angry?
لماذا أنت غاضبة جدًا؟
This is the way I talk
هذه هي الطريقة التي أتحدث بها
and I'm not angry.
ولست غاضبة
No offense, Mr. Lin.
لا جريمة يا سيد لين
Well, I thought too much, then.
حسنا، فكرت في الكثير، إذن
Oh, Miss Qianqian,
أوه، الآنسة تشيان
I'm here to send a message.
أنا هنا لإرسال رسالة
Wen Yu invited Her Grace out for a talk.
ون يو دعا غريس إلى الخروج للحديث
Wen Yu invited Her Grace?
وين يو دعا غريطها؟
Yes. And Wen Yu
نعم، ووين يو
invited her alone.
دعاها وحده
Alone?
بمفردك؟
How can he do that? I...
كيف له أن يفعل ذلك؟ أنا...
Miss Qianqian, please tell Her Grace about it.
الآنسة تشيان، يرجى إخبار صاحبة غريس عن ذلك
(Silver Note of Beishuo Bank)
(ملحوظة فضية من مصرف "بيشو")
How much money has Xingyi spent?
كم أنفق شينغ يي؟
I can hardly raise him.
لا أستطيع رؤيته
Your Grace.
عرشك
Your Grace, Mr. Lin is here.
السيد لين هنا
He brought a message for Wen Yu,
وجلب رسالة إلى وين يو
inviting you out.
تدعوك إلى الخارج
Why did Lin Mu send the message?
لماذا أرسل لين مو الرسالة؟
He came, indeed.
لقد جاء بالفعل
He also said, Wen Yu only invited you.
وقال أيضا، ون يو دعاك فقط
Your Grace, you may be in danger out there.
غريسك، قد تكون في خطر هناك
How about I reject him?
ماذا عن أن أرفضه؟
Don't.
لا تفعل ذلك
When Wen Yu is around,
عندما يكون وين يو في الجوار
I won't be in danger.
لن أكون في خطر
Don't worry. Come on.
لا تقلق، هيا
Go pick a nice dress for me.
اذهب واختر ثوبًا لطيفًا لي
But…
لكن...
Su Nian, he is here.
سو نيان، إنه هنا
I get it. Leave us.
فهمت، اتركنا
Greetings, gentleman.
تحياتي أيها الرجل النبيل
I mistook you for someone else.
أنا ظننت أنك لشخص آخر
I'm... I'm sorry.
أنا آسفة
Gentleman,
أيها السيد
there seems to be...
يبدو أن هناك
A misunderstanding between us.
سوء تفاهم بيننا
We... We should keep our distance.
يجب أن نحافظ على بعدنا
Be seated, please.
اجلس من فضلك
In the House of Romance, you once protected me.
في مجلس الرومانسية، كنت تحميني ذات مرة
I'm really grateful.
أنا ممتن حقًا
So, I prepared some wine.
لذلك، جهزت بعض النبيذ
Hope
آمل
you can let go of what happened
يمكنك التخلي عما حدث
and drink with me.
وأشرب معي
Before, I mistook you for an assassin.
من قبل، ظننت أنك قاتل
So, we are...
لذلك، نحن...
We are even.
نحن متعادلان
Now, our misunderstanding is gone.
الآن، اختفى سوء الفهم بيننا
I'll take my leave, then.
سأغادر إذًا
Do you really dislike me this much?
هل أنت حقًا لا تحبينني إلى هذا الحد؟
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحًا
Yeah.
نعم
I'm from a humble family
أنا من عائلة متواضعة
and now I'm a musician.
وأنا موسيقي
Who will
من سيقوم
really protect me?
يحميني حقًا؟
No.
لا
We Dongyu people
نحن شعب دونغيو
don't have a hierarchy.
ليس لديهم التسلسل الهرمي
- Is that true? - I never lie.
- هل هذا صحيح؟ - لا أكذب أبدا
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
please drink with me.
أرجوك اشربي معي
All right.
حسنًا
A... A toast to you.
شرب لك
Come have a look. Sachets for sale.
تعالي وألق نظرة، أكياس للبيع
I'm going to fly a kite, too.
سأبيع طباخي أيضًا
Pendants for sale.
بنداران للبيع
Sir, come have a look.
سيدي، تعال وألق نظرة
What are you looking at?
إلام تنظرين؟
Look.
انظر
Sir, how many fish have you caught?
سيدي، كم عدد السمك الذي أمسكت به؟
One.
واحد
I've got more than half a bucket.
لديّ أكثر من نصف دلو
Look, the bucket is nearly full.
انظري، السترة ممتلئة تقريبًا
Tonight, come to my home for some wine.
الليلة، تعالي إلى منزلي لشراء بعض النبيذ
All right. I'll be there.
حسنًا، سأصل
It's such a great life.
الحياة رائعة
Yeah.
نعم
It's great.
إنه رائع
♪Clouds slowly float across the sky♪
♪ الغيوم تطفو ببطء عبر السماء ♪
♪Telling what is awfully bothering♪
♪ وضع ما يزعج كثيرا ♪
♪Ceaseless, love lingers and lingers♪
♪ لا يتوقف، أحب الأمور المتبقية والدائمة ♪
♪You and I both know it♪
♪ أنا وأنت نعرف ذلك ♪
♪In this world, we stay side by side♪
♪ في هذا العالم، نبقى جنبا إلى جنب ♪
♪Watching the stars rise and fall♪
♪ مشاهدة النجوم ترتفع وتنخفض ♪
♪My eyes are red from missing you♪
♪ عيني أحمر من غيابكم ♪
♪Tonight, I hope the moonlight will♪
♪ ليلة، آمل أن يكون ضوء القمر ♪
♪Kiss your eyebrows♪
♪ قبلة حاجباك ♪
♪I'll always be in love with you♪
♪ سأكون دائمًا في حبك ♪
♪Promising it'll last forever♪
♪ مؤشر على أنها ستدوم إلى الأبد ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ مع ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪Leaving a wish to be fulfilled♪
♪ إنقاذ أمنية يتعين تحقيقها ♪
♪To have joy for the rest of its life♪
♪ للفخر لبقية حياتها ♪
♪I'll stay with you for thousands of years♪
♪ سأبقى معك بآلاف السنين ♪
♪Until we grow old together♪
♪ حتى نتقدم في السن معا ♪
♪As the breeze blows, the flower fades♪
♪ كما ضربات النسيم، تتلاشى الزهرة ♪
♪When I look back, you whisper♪
♪ عندما أنظر إلى الوراء، أنت أتذمر ♪
♪Then I wake up from the dream♪
♪ إذن أستيقظ من الحلم ♪
♪Like how we met for the first time♪
♪ مثل كيفية التقينا للمرة الأولى ♪